We'll call the order. The regular scheduled meeting of the University Council for Monday, September 19th, 2022.
We're number two, Proclamation, Recognizing Hank Albertson, David Bowdine, Leslie Dixon, Lance Fields, Ignacio Lopez, Jr., Andrea Soluch, for their military service.
And they will be in my amma with Jack Dowder and Paul and these court-bottomed sportsman association, or the deer hunt that's coming up.
The great deer hunt is what's called for paralyzed veterans, with a mid-America chapter.
So Jack is here to accept these and we're going to come down and present those in front here and get some pictures real quick.
We're going to stay down here for number three, the
Proclamation Recognizing Bobby Crawford or Bobby Carter for outstanding
community service and for those of you in the no Bob you know the work that he puts in
for a rodeo every year and he's brought his crew here. I know we couldn't do it without the
end and that's why they're here. But 13 years in a row it's been rodeo of the year
and you know I didn't really know that meant until this last rodeo I ran into the
the guy that does the announcing at the end of the rodeo and talked to him for just a little bit
and he told me that he does rodeo is all over all of the country I guess and he said this was
the best one they do and he said you don't understand what I'm saying he said we do Pro rodeo
that aren't this good and he said you're crew here my Emma does an outstanding job put this
together he's always looking forward to coming here for this he's a plus you guys have the best crowds
that we see anywhere so and that goes straight back to Bob and his crew for the effort they put in it's not I
I mean I know we help
financially and all that but we have nothing to do with what they what they get done, what they pull off and we appreciate that
Because it brings people to our community that might never come here for anything else and so we wanted to recognize you and your team and we appreciate all you do force
I did it that way. I learned to find out she's pretty sharp
But I mean without the city Miami the colleagues and our sponsors. I mean there is no way
We can make this happen. I mean we reach out to anybody and we'll in the hell and we go to the road
I mean we go to the safety rodeo's year and there is nothing that matches life is
Why don't you get your city to help?
I see the morning I can do it best because we're sitting on a get it. I mean tourism
That it's huge and stay up a little bit and people don't get it
And I mean they get the effort and get the group of people like we've got
We've probably got 13 14 guys when the committee that are willing to help we said that we've got the college
We've got the city. I mean we've got a great bunch of guys, great bunch of girls, great bunch of volunteers
My problem is that it is the best rodeo in the forced stay there. I'm almost
I told this last week that our last meeting in college and here someone told again
But I saw Kyle's rodeo this year and afterwards he told me how good our rodeo was
And he said it was the first time he'd been
He might have rode up his rodeo. He'd be driven home. Maybe rodeo
But he was talking about how great ours was so that means something coming from a guy
It's been a rodeo all his life to say how good our
So we appreciate everybody
You know we got problems now
We're in our conditions and we're running out of bathrooms
But we're finding ways to face that
We appreciate everything the city does not come
We're seeing
Yeah, we're seeing
And before the public input or on scheduled personal appearances, we have none.
Five, consider agenda staff recommends we approve item six and seven.
Eight, award bid C-22-46 for annual, as needed on call, open trench and boring labor.
For water line replacements to be-town, construction, construction, goings and rises,
Cooper, resources, route head boring, hasco, fabrication and construction.
Now, approve contract, continue to upon the submission, required contract documents,
and approve city manager, or his days in need to sign to proceed.
I'm so this is for water line replacements.
We've previously approved it on the MS2A side.
This is just a premium on the city side.
Thank you.
Now, I'm in service agreement with Tyler Technologist and Corporate Migrate,
the city's financial software encode to the Tyler Technology Cloud environment in the middle of one.
106,428 dollars.
Thank you.
Hi.
10, resolution, CC 2022-11 for community finance and support and fee waivers to the Mime Club of Schools,
for construction projects located in the city of Miami.
Good evening.
So this is the resolution we talked about at the last council meeting that would wave.
If you guys spoke to approve this would wave all building and permit fees for any
construction project from Miami Public Schools.
All right.
Thank you, Christine.
11, declare the proposed items listed in the packet at surplus and authorize the items to be offered for sale
through online auction or authorize their destruction to protect sensitive information.
So you have in the your packets the list of the items that city staff has asked to have surplus and we're going to sell what we can sell.
and the staff that computer staff that has confidential information on will be destroyed.
But we have to declare it surplus before we can do either of those.
Oh, Mike, motion to approve.
All right.
13 other new business of many, which is a residence in the posting list agenda.
I'm going to mark it off, right. Sorry.
All right, I already have marked off.
Order of 2022, that's well.
The pending and rewriting chapter four.
Oh yeah.
I know about this one. Sorry.
Chapter four, animals.
The code of ordinances, providing severability, providing for conflicting provisions,
repealing all conflicting ordinances and establishing in effective date.
We know you all have anxiously awaited getting this ordinance,
not near as much as we've anxiously awaited getting it to you.
This is the ordinance that we talked to you about at the city session month or so ago.
We can answer any questions you might have.
Again, the two major things that would be changes from the current law is it has the provisions for
catch, neuter and return for the feral cats.
That is probably the most immediate problem that we have here in the city.
Then the other major provision is for a mandatory neuter provision.
Now, what the plan going forward is we're hoping if you approve this to implement it in 30 days.
The ordinance would not go into effect for 30 days during that time period.
We'll start the publicity and start educating the public about what all is entailed with this
ordinance change when that 30 days arrives.
We're still not going to fully implement everything we're going to take it step by step.
But the first provision that we're going to implement would be the feral cat problem,
which we get lots of complaints about.
It strengthens and then other parks will be implemented as we move forward.
I could go on because it covers a lot of things.
I do need to add that since you the packet was sent out and you receive.
copy, actually found a few other errors or typographical errors, I should say, and so there
have been some minor changes since what you've got, but the just of everything remains the
same as what you got. With that, the AC and I and Kevin would be glad to answer any questions.
I do need to add, as I'm sure all of you are aware last weekend, we had a significant
issue happen with some vicious dogs. This doesn't substantially change how that situation
would be handled, but it does give us more leeway and how we deal with these problems. Since
that incident has happened, one of the things that has happened here in the community is
a lot of people with that read of dog or now wanting to turn them in, give them up to
the city, the pound or the shelter, I should say, is full, it's besting at the seams,
we can't take all the ones that people are wanting to turn in. Anyway, the hope is that through
this process, over time, it will reduce the costs that we're having with the entire animal
shelter and the animal control situation. It's not going to happen immediately, in fact, probably
the costs will go up a little bit for a while, but at least the experiences from other communities
that have implemented these types of programs, over time, it begins to reduce and significantly
reduce the cost of operating an animal control system like what we hoped to have here in my
am I? I'm not understanding this. Or it also gives Macy and her team the ability to write
to get the association? Yes. Before they had to not have that capability. That is correct. Up until now,
everything has been done through the police department. That's burdensome on both entities,
both animal control and the police department, so they will be able to write citations. It sets
the foundation for another aspect of this that we want to do and that's ultimately to have
community development, code compliance to be able to write citations just like we're going to be doing
through animal control here. That's how you support...
Make sure that you have anything you'd want to add.
Kevin, you got anything you want to add?
I'll take it.
All right.
Senator.
Hi.
All right.
Now 13.
The other new business of any, which is a resistance,
supposing of this agenda, 14 staff reports, 15 mayor, council, community, and
announcements.
This won't say, I don't know if you have some of my video today, we've got a little ice cream
place in town, rolling cold, it's called 130 North Maine, local guy has opened that store
up.
Went in, he's pretty swamped.
He was, I think he got a 45-minute wait that they all went, and he only takes cash right
now, so that was a problem for me, and I didn't have a cash, and my grandkids went in a
wait 45 minutes.
So we were going to go back and let her date, but it sounds like he's doing pretty well, he's got a
long wait, most of the time, because people are trying to get in there.
You have to take his Facebook page for his hour to think he changed him recently, but I think
it's like 10 a morning to 9, Monday through Saturday, and then 10 to 2 or 3 on Sunday, so
he's going to be able to spend some days a week, but a little cool place here in town, so you
can't stop by and check him out.
May I?
16, City Manager Communication.
I don't have anything to add.
17.
Jeremy.